Linna, let's go!
So, this is Tokyo?
Linna!
All right!
If you're late, the acting supervisor
will make a big deal out of it.
So it would be a good idea to sneak in.
You don't need to take tea to the
salespeople when they aren't here.
I used to see this city on TV, but it's
even more incredible in person.
It's only been six years since
the earthquake,
but the city's revived and grown
so huge, so fast!
Excuse me!
No, it is I who am sorry.
Oh, sorry.
You don't need to apologize to a boomer
even if you are a new employee.
But weren't the boomers the power
behind the reconstruction?
I've never seen one close up like that!
Oh no! We've got to go buy our lunch!
Wait! How can you tell?
From the shadow.
Under the auspices of the
Genom Corporation,
construction of the Showhamm Project
has steadily progressed in orbit.
The Showhamm Project is an ambitious
endeavor to save the world,
by solving all of our energy needs.
We anticipate its completion to usher
in our advance into the next century.
Hey, haven't you ever seen them?
What do you mean by ''them''?
The Knight Sabers! They're so cool!
You mean you really believe that
''champions of justice'' actually exist?
It's a rumor, just a rumor.
But I used to watch them on the
net in my home town.
If they actually existed, the television
news would do a report on them.
I've never seen any news
reports on them.
Rumor? That's it?
I'm sorry to have kept you
waiting so long.
Oh, thanks!
Thank you very much.
Somehow, I can't help hating boomers.
I don't see why they have to
look like humans.
They could look like robots,
couldn't they?
I think it's supposed to make it easier
for us to be friendly with them.
Oh boy, you're a klutz, aren't you?
Do you want to go back, and
get another sandwich.
Hold it right there!
Hey, stop it!
What are you going to do
about my lunch?
Linna, cut it out! She didn't hit you!
You should pay for it.
Pay me back for my lunch!
Oh, no.
What is it?
You shouldn't get involved
with someone like that.
Tokyo isn't the little town
where you grew up.
I won't forgive her!
Linna, don't be late, okay?
Damn, it's difficult to run
with these shoes on!
I won't endure an insult like this
the minute I move to Tokyo!
Running away?
Where is your shoe?
You can't work looking like that.
Your makeup is a mess as well.
You can't see customers like that.
I think I'm starting to dislike boomers.
I'm a boomer, but I have a responsibility
to educate new employees.
Such statements will affect
your assessment,
so you should avoid saying
things like that.
Yes, yes.
One yes is enough.
Yes, yes, yes!
Damn it! Why me?
Why do I have to be ordered
around by a boomer?
Is that the brave new employee
in the Second Sales Division?
Yes, my name is Linna Yamazaki.
I heard you're new to Tokyo?
Yes, I am. I thought I knew enough about
Tokyo from watching television,
but now that I'm living here, it
seems completely different!
Well, shall I give you a little
tour of the city tonight?
What? Where?
There are lots of interesting
places in Megalocity.
This is Bravo Tango. Situation normal.
Bravo Tango, roger. Return to tower.
Nothing to do again today.
We haven't had any mad boomer
incidents recently, have we?
We'd be in trouble if they happened
too often, but it's been so slow,
I've started thinking about
finding another job.
What kind of job do you want, Nene?
Well, I want to be more
active physically.
For example?
For example...
Knight Sabers!
Or something like that.
Are you an idiot?
Totem Pole, can you hear me?
This is the AD Police Intelligence
Agency, Management Center.
Next time you call here with a weird
nickname, I won't answer, Leon-chan!
Leon-chan, is it?
I haven't sunk so low that eighteen year
old girls can give me nicknames.
There are no mad boomers
in Sodo Ward today.
Roger. It's quitting time,
so I'm going home.
She acts like a part timer, doesn't she?
We're supposed to be a SWAT team.
Instead we're just a clean up
team for boomer messes.
Not to mention the obnoxious people
who take even those away from us.
Just thinking about them drives me mad.
Damn those Knight Sabers!
After sinking during the earthquake,
this area was beneath the attention
of city planners.
But it was also the first area
to recover: Sodo Ward.
It's incredible, isn't it?
This is where the desires
of adults are fulfilled.
No matter what your desire,
if you want it bad enough, it can
happen, but it'll cost you.
Really? That's a little scary.
Uh, boss?
We're not in the office, so
you can call me Kane.
Have you heard of those champions who
appear when a boomer goes berserk?
Knight something, you mean?
They're annoying!
They do a lot of damage to
our company image,
since we're involved with the
boomer industry.
It's just not possible for boomers
to go berserk.
But, should something happen,
there's the AD Police.
I consider them to be a dangerous
vigilante group.
Are you one of their stupid fans?
I...
That woman...
Well, why don't we stop talking
about work tonight?
Let's have fun.
Lady Sylia, please come to the pit.
We've confirmed the reaction.
What's this? You have an injury here.
Oh, I had a small fall.
You need to take good care of your face.
Excuse me, but what time do you have?
It's hard to tell at night since we can't
see the shadow of the sky hook.
You live by yourself, don't you?
Don't you think it's rude to worry about
when it's time to go home?
I'm sorry!
Why am I apologizing to him?
Geez, what bad timing this is!
It's here!
Excuse me, I'm going home!
What's wrong? The night will
last a long time, and well...
And well what?
You know, I'm in charge of the
assessment of new employees.
Keep in mind that your position will be
affected by what I tell the chief.
So, you're the supervisor who gets
a feel for new employees?
What did you say?
A mad boomer?!
Boss?!
Get out of my way!
What a jerk!
Is there an AD Fronter near Sodo Ward?
This is Leon.
There's a mad boomer at Pace
Brook in Sodo Ward.
We have a request from the
regular police to dispatch.
We have to go back there,
don't we? Geez...
Why the hell are you upset?!
I don't want them to get there
ahead of us again!
There's an exit over there!
Why do you have to be chasing me?!
Let's play! Hey, let's
clean up and play!
Oh, no! Hurry up, Priss, let's go.
Don't be so much trouble.
You already checked your
self-starter, didn't you?
Pay attention to each other's gauge
at all times! Do you understand?
I heard already!
I've got it on. I'm going.
Destroy it, completely!
Why do you have to target me?!
Oh, no!
Knight Sabers!
No way! Are you saying I have to jump?!
Hey! Wait a second!
Oh, God. All right!
Leon, we're late. Again.
Damn!
Yet another peaceful morning
dawns in Megalocity.
Citizens, please give thanks that you're
able to live in such a peaceful city.
This program is presented by the Genom
Corp., the leaders in boomer technology.
That's all of my report.
See you at the usual meeting next week.
Hi, it was rough last night, wasn't it?
I looked for you. Anyway,
I'm glad you're okay.
Thank you for everything last night.
Thank goodness you're okay!
I would like to express my
appreciation to you, so...
Well, tonight, perhaps?
No, I'd like to do it right now.
This is my appreciation!
Priss, why don't you have
a drink tonight?
Next time.
Damn, you say that all the time!
Thanks anyway! You were
great as always tonight!
Who's there?
What are you going to do about my scar?
It will heal soon.
You're a Knight Saber, aren't you?
I want to be a Knight Saber too.
Wait!
I want to be a member of
the Knight Sabers.
Even though it's been beyond my grasp,
I've been longing for it.
But now the opportunity is right in
front of me, so I'll do my best!
I was able to meet Priss, but
she ran away from me.
I chased her, but lost her after awhile.
The next thing I found was...
What a surprise!
Next Bubblegum Crisis!