1
00:00:06,950 --> 00:00:09,910
前情提要

2
00:00:11,580 --> 00:00:13,120
你是我的一切
You are my world.

3
00:00:15,790 --> 00:00:17,080
你要带他去哪里
Where are you taking him?

4
00:00:17,080 --> 00:00:18,500
去真实世界
To the real world.

5
00:00:18,500 --> 00:00:19,870
哪天你也该去那里看看
You should see it sometime.

6
00:00:20,370 --> 00:00:26,330
如果你能带我找到摩尔达弗 你就能改变未来
You can change the future if you can bring me to Moldaver.

7
00:00:27,200 --> 00:00:28,370
只要带我的头去就够了
Just my head.

8
00:00:29,250 --> 00:00:31,500
只有这样你才能把你爸爸救出来
This is the only way to get your dad back.

9
00:00:32,910 --> 00:00:35,370
戴恩候补生 你知道他的伤势吗
Aspirant Dane? You're aware of their injury?

10
00:00:36,790 --> 00:00:37,790
打死它
Shoot it!

11
00:00:38,330 --> 00:00:41,120
你这个蠢货 全都怪你
You stupid motherfucker, you know this is all your fault.

12
00:00:41,620 --> 00:00:42,450
他们会杀了你
They'll kill you for this.

13
00:00:42,450 --> 00:00:44,250
但我们可以瞒过他们
They don't have to find out.

14
00:00:44,250 --> 00:00:46,830
他们可是兄弟会啊 他们一定会发现的
It's the Brotherhood. They'll find out.

15
00:00:47,500 --> 00:00:50,040
他们想要脑袋  那我就给他们一颗脑袋
They want a head, we give them a head.

16
00:00:50,040 --> 00:00:53,500
- 你应该和我一起回去 - 他们永远不会停止寻找
You're supposed to come with me. They're never gonna stop looking. Trust me.

17
00:00:55,580 --> 00:00:58,290
美国一直被困在资源战争中
America has been locked in a resource war.

18
00:00:58,290 --> 00:01:01,120
避难所科技公司买下了 所有能终结战争的发明
Vault-Tec bought the means to end that war.

19
00:01:01,120 --> 00:01:03,870
冷核聚变 无限能量
Cold fusion. Infinite energy.

20
00:01:03,870 --> 00:01:06,000
- 那难道是... - 聚变核心
- Is-is that a... - Fusion core?

21
00:01:06,120 --> 00:01:08,830
这些东西现在很罕见 不是吗
You don't see those around much anymore, do you?

22
00:01:08,830 --> 00:01:12,330
想要摧毁你的竞争对手 最重要的武器什么
What is the ultimate weapon to destroy your competition?

23
00:01:12,330 --> 00:01:13,660
是时间
It's time.

24
00:01:13,660 --> 00:01:16,250
你想过去别的地方工作吗
You ever think about working somewhere else?

25
00:01:16,250 --> 00:01:18,160
但是有没有我 避难所科技都会存在
Vault-Tec exists with or without me.

26
00:01:18,160 --> 00:01:21,330
我这样的小员工 抱怨他是不会有好下场的
It doesn't do anyone any good to complain from the sidelines.

27
00:01:21,330 --> 00:01:23,040
这是监听设备
It's a listening device.

28
00:01:23,040 --> 00:01:25,120
你想让我监听我妻子吗
You want me to spy on my wife?

29
00:01:25,120 --> 00:01:27,160
她的哔哔小子怎么处理的
When my mother died, what happened to her Pip-Boy?

30
00:01:27,160 --> 00:01:28,500
和她埋在一起了
It was buried with her.

31
00:01:28,950 --> 00:01:30,450
因为我亲手埋葬的她
I buried her myself.

32
00:01:30,450 --> 00:01:32,000
我需要返回31号

33
00:01:32,000 --> 00:01:33,700
我和你父亲一起
Me... and your father.

34
00:01:39,410 --> 00:01:40,410
你好
Hello?

35
00:02:20,700 --> 00:02:21,830
来找我
Find me.

36
00:02:22,870 --> 00:02:23,870
我会的
I will.

37
00:02:40,950 --> 00:02:43,660
费城

38
00:02:45,040 --> 00:02:46,700
费城已经可以降落了
Filly clear for landing.

39
00:02:46,700 --> 00:02:49,790
当地人顽强抵抗 但我们打败了他们
The locals put up a fight, but so did we.

40
00:03:56,870 --> 00:03:58,910
你穿着骑士的红制服
You're wearing the Knight's red.

41
00:04:01,000 --> 00:04:02,330
你的骑士在哪里
Where's your Knight?

42
00:04:06,120 --> 00:04:07,620
他死了
He's dead.

43
00:04:12,160 --> 00:04:14,750
这不是第一次了
This is not the first time a Brother in your company

44
00:04:14,750 --> 00:04:18,870
从前就有一位成员 在你的陪伴下遭遇不幸
has fallen into misfortune...

45
00:04:21,830 --> 00:04:23,370
不是吗
...is it?

46
00:04:33,700 --> 00:04:36,330
恐怕你那次就撒谎了
I fear you lied then.

47
00:04:37,580 --> 00:04:39,410
不是工艺品 大人
No artifact, m'lord.

48
00:04:40,790 --> 00:04:42,790
就像你现在也在撒谎
Just as you lie now.

49
00:04:44,870 --> 00:04:46,660
等等
Wait, wait, wait!

50
00:04:47,410 --> 00:04:49,120
等等
Wait, wait, wait.

51
00:04:49,950 --> 00:04:53,330
请听我说 我能帮你找到真的脑袋
Please, listen to me! I can get you the real head.

52
00:04:54,910 --> 00:04:57,750
- 说实话 - 不要杀我 我能带你去找脑袋
Confess. Don't kill me and I can lead you to it!

53
00:05:06,160 --> 00:05:07,250
我能帮你
I can help you!

54
00:05:07,750 --> 00:05:09,160
饶了他吧 大人
Please, m'lord.

55
00:05:10,620 --> 00:05:12,950
伤害我的人是我自己 与他无关
My injury was my own doing. Not his.

56
00:05:14,750 --> 00:05:17,500
求你了 我知道脑袋在哪里
Please... Please, I know where the head is!

57
00:05:17,500 --> 00:05:19,910
为了兄弟会 请相信他的话
For the sake of the Brotherhood, please listen to him!

58
00:05:22,750 --> 00:05:25,200
你真是好忠诚啊
Such a display of loyalty.

59
00:05:26,040 --> 00:05:28,660
如今很少见了
Don't see that much anymore.

60
00:05:58,500 --> 00:06:02,330
你以为你是第一个 觊觎骑士装甲的扈从吗
You think you're the first squire who coveted his Knight's armor?

61
00:06:05,540 --> 00:06:07,750
提图斯怎么死的
How did Titus die?

62
00:06:07,750 --> 00:06:09,830
他逃跑时死掉的
He died running.

63
00:06:13,330 --> 00:06:15,750
兄弟会已经不复往昔
The Brotherhood has lost its way.

64
00:06:17,580 --> 00:06:20,580
我们曾是废土的统治者
We once ruled the Wasteland...

65
00:06:24,410 --> 00:06:28,500
权力要靠抢 不能等着他人给予
And yet power is taken, not given.

66
00:06:28,500 --> 00:06:31,000
看起来这个理念你已经学到了
A lesson you seem to have learned.

67
00:06:39,750 --> 00:06:41,620
如果你说的是真话
So, if what you say is true,

68
00:06:43,500 --> 00:06:45,250
如果你能带我们找到遗物
and you can lead us to the relic,

69
00:06:46,620 --> 00:06:50,160
那我将和你一起
then together, you and I,

70
00:06:50,160 --> 00:06:52,870
掌握大权
we will take power.

71
00:06:54,580 --> 00:06:55,910
有了它
And with it...

72
00:06:57,370 --> 00:07:02,750
我们将创建新的兄弟会 我将成为首领
we will start a new Brotherhood. With me as its head,

73
00:07:02,750 --> 00:07:06,410
你这样的成员则会成为战士
and the likes of you as its sword.

74
00:07:15,370 --> 00:07:18,700
你这一生都在寻找一个家
Your entire life, you've been looking for a home.

75
00:07:28,790 --> 00:07:31,000
我们能一起创建一个
Build one with me.

76
00:07:55,620 --> 00:07:56,580
导航

77
00:07:56,580 --> 00:07:58,750
您已到达目的地

78
00:08:34,250 --> 00:08:35,040
是她
It's her.

79
00:08:46,910 --> 00:08:50,370
格里菲斯天文台

80
00:09:15,830 --> 00:09:20,250
避难所科技公司

81
00:09:24,910 --> 00:09:26,750
谢谢你送我一程
Well, thank you for the ride.

82
00:09:26,750 --> 00:09:30,290
毕竟我没能帮你换好油 总要弥补你一下
Well, it's the least I could do after I bungled your oil change.

83
00:09:30,290 --> 00:09:32,750
你愿意尝试 我已经很感谢了
Well, I appreciate you trying.

84
00:09:32,750 --> 00:09:36,290
大部分开得起这种豪车的男人
You know, most guys with a ride this nice,

85
00:09:36,290 --> 00:09:38,830
都不愿意弄脏双手
they wouldn't be willing to get their hands dirty.

86
00:09:41,410 --> 00:09:43,450
- 好的 - 好的
Okay.

87
00:09:43,450 --> 00:09:45,370
- 我爱你 - 我也爱你
- I love you. - Love you, too.

88
00:09:47,200 --> 00:09:49,200
- 祝你一天愉快 - 谢谢 库珀
- Have a great day. - Thank you, Coop.

89
00:09:49,200 --> 00:09:50,370
好的
Okay.

90
00:10:00,250 --> 00:10:02,660
库珀 嘿
Coop!

91
00:10:04,080 --> 00:10:06,410
- 很高兴见到你 兄弟 - 是啊
- Good to see you, buddy. - Yeah.

92
00:10:07,410 --> 00:10:08,500
怎么了
What's wrong?

93
00:10:08,500 --> 00:10:11,660
我的哔哔小子好像出问题了Uh, my Pip-Boy. It's been acting strange.

94
00:10:12,250 --> 00:10:14,330
发射器一直处于激活状态
The transmitter is always activated...

95
00:10:14,330 --> 00:10:17,040
给技术部的人看看吧
Well, maybe take it over to the boys in IT, have them take a look...

96
00:10:17,040 --> 00:10:19,120
没事 我自己能搞定
No, no, I can fix it myself.

97
00:10:19,120 --> 00:10:21,620
我只需要查出哔哔小子 在往哪里发送信号
I just need to figure out where the Pip-Boy is trying to transmit to...

98
00:10:21,620 --> 00:10:24,290
我该走了 我答应了珍妮 要教她甩套索
I-I'm heading out. I promised Janey that I would teach her some roping.

99
00:10:24,290 --> 00:10:26,450
是吗 我现在还没有孩子
Oh, yeah? I don't have kids myself.

100
00:10:26,450 --> 00:10:29,080
不过我要负责新晋高管项目
But I do have a training program for up-and-coming executives,

101
00:10:29,080 --> 00:10:31,000
和养孩子几乎没什么区别
and that's basically the same thing.

102
00:10:31,000 --> 00:10:32,790
芭波和你说过这事吧
I imagine Barb told you about it?

103
00:10:35,580 --> 00:10:36,830
没有
Uh... no. No.

104
00:10:36,830 --> 00:10:38,160
我称之为“巴德的伙伴们”
Well, I call it Bud's Buds.

105
00:10:38,160 --> 00:10:40,700
基本思想就是 人类寿命的短暂
The basic idea is that the biggest obstacle to achievement

106
00:10:40,700 --> 00:10:42,620
是取得成就的最大障碍
has been the brevity of the human lifespan.

107
00:10:42,620 --> 00:10:45,450
这让我们无法开展耗时几个世纪
It's prevented us from working on projects that require centuries,

108
00:10:45,450 --> 00:10:47,080
甚至一千年的项目
maybe even millennia, to see through.

109
00:10:47,080 --> 00:10:50,000
所以理想情况下 “巴德的伙伴们”能让我的项目
So ideally, Bud's Buds will keep my project on track

110
00:10:50,000 --> 00:10:52,500
顺利发展好几个世纪 多棒啊
- centuries into the future. Nifty, huh? - Bud.

111
00:10:52,500 --> 00:10:53,830
- 我们要迟到了 - 是啊
- We're getting late. - Oh, yes.

112
00:10:53,830 --> 00:10:55,950
- 走吧 - 今天是个大日子
- Let's go. - Big day today.

113
00:10:55,950 --> 00:10:58,250
是啊 祝你们好运
Yeah. Good luck.

114
00:11:03,450 --> 00:11:07,330
咱们哪天一起去卡巴那咖啡馆吧
Hey, maybe, uh, maybe we could all go to Café Cabana sometime?

115
00:11:07,330 --> 00:11:08,540
你 我 还有库珀
You, me and Coop?

116
00:11:08,540 --> 00:11:10,200
不好意思
Sorry.

117
00:11:10,200 --> 00:11:12,750
你的哔哔小子有出问题吗
Has your Pip-Boy been acting strangely?

118
00:11:12,750 --> 00:11:14,500
没有 你的怎么了
No. Why? What's wrong with yours?

119
00:11:14,500 --> 00:11:17,620
我不确定 你...
I'm not sure yet.

120
00:11:17,620 --> 00:11:19,120
靠
Fuck.

121
00:11:46,200 --> 00:11:52,200
辐射
第一季第八集

122
00:11:46,200 --> 00:11:52,200
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并

123
00:12:15,160 --> 00:12:16,160
露西
Lucy.

124
00:12:17,000 --> 00:12:18,160
爸爸
Dad.

125
00:12:30,450 --> 00:12:31,620
欢迎
Welcome.

126
00:12:44,660 --> 00:12:47,750
请坐吧 该我款待你了 不是吗
Join us. It's my turn to host, isn't it?

127
00:12:54,290 --> 00:12:56,790
对于这一刻 我思考了好长时间
I've had a lot of time to think about this moment.

128
00:12:59,870 --> 00:13:02,790
你肯定不相信我思考过哪些事情
You wouldn't believe the things that went through my head.

129
00:13:06,700 --> 00:13:12,200
有天晚上 我甚至想要 往脖子的洞里塞个旧手榴弹
One night, I... actually tried to stuff an old grenade into the neck hole.

130
00:13:15,830 --> 00:13:18,950
我打算走进这里
Guess I... was gonna walk in here and...

131
00:13:18,950 --> 00:13:22,040
把大家都炸死
blow everybody up.

132
00:13:22,910 --> 00:13:27,160
但我从小到大受到的不是那种教育
But it's... not really how I was raised.

133
00:13:30,830 --> 00:13:34,200
如果你不介意的话
So... if you don't mind,

134
00:13:34,200 --> 00:13:36,290
我希望能和平解决这件事
I'm gonna keep things civil.

135
00:13:41,200 --> 00:13:44,290
就像你要求的那样 我把你朋友带来了
Brought you your friend. Just like he asked.

136
00:13:57,040 --> 00:13:58,870
现在 拜托
Now, please...

137
00:14:00,250 --> 00:14:01,910
把我爸爸还给我
...give me my dad back.

138
00:14:04,160 --> 00:14:05,580
非常好
Very well.

139
00:14:13,160 --> 00:14:14,790
但是
But, first...

140
00:14:17,620 --> 00:14:21,200
想不想知道 我和你爸爸是怎么认识的
...what if I tell you how I know your father?

141
00:14:21,200 --> 00:14:22,830
你爸爸真正的身份
Who he really is?

142
00:14:25,580 --> 00:14:28,160
不 露西 不要听
No. Lucy, don't listen to her.

143
00:14:28,160 --> 00:14:31,160
你以为你父亲是在避难所出生的
You think your father was born in a vault.

144
00:14:31,830 --> 00:14:33,250
就像你一样
Like you.

145
00:14:36,000 --> 00:14:37,620
就像你的弟弟
Like your brother.

146
00:14:38,330 --> 00:14:41,370
未来...这次我一定能搞定
The key to the future of-- No, no, I'll get it this time.

147
00:14:41,370 --> 00:14:42,750
你好
Hello?

148
00:14:42,750 --> 00:14:44,540
未来的关键...
The key to the future of humanity--

149
00:14:46,080 --> 00:14:47,950
人类未来的关键...
The-the-the key to the future of human--

150
00:14:49,450 --> 00:14:50,540
这太荒谬了
This is ridiculous.

151
00:14:51,580 --> 00:14:53,450
人类未来的关键...
The key to the future of humanity-- Nope. Try.

152
00:14:55,830 --> 00:14:56,660
有人吗
- Hello? - Nope.

153
00:14:58,330 --> 00:15:00,120
人类未来的关键...
The key to the future of humanity--

154
00:15:00,120 --> 00:15:03,410
我能搞定的 我可以的 不用担心
Ugh, I'm gonna get it. I'll get it. Don't you worry.

155
00:15:04,080 --> 00:15:06,620
未来...人类未来的关键...
The key to-- the key to the future of humanity--

156
00:15:08,620 --> 00:15:10,290
这太荒谬了
Now this is just ridiculous.

157
00:15:11,120 --> 00:15:13,040
再来 在这场盛大的游戏...
A great game of the--

158
00:15:14,750 --> 00:15:16,120
抱歉
All right, all right,

159
00:15:16,120 --> 00:15:19,000
这次肯定行了 我能搞定的
this one's it. I'll get it this time.

160
00:15:19,000 --> 00:15:20,950
人类未来的关键...
The key to the future of humanity is a--

161
00:15:21,620 --> 00:15:23,700
不行 也许我必须...
Uh, nope. Just maybe I have to--

162
00:15:25,330 --> 00:15:26,540
谢谢你 贝蒂
Thank you, Betty.

163
00:15:28,120 --> 00:15:31,370
等等 你不是贝蒂 也不是汉克
Wait, you're not Betty. Or Hank.

164
00:15:32,580 --> 00:15:35,910
你的DNA只有一半 与汉克麦克莱恩相似
You share only 50% of Hank MacLean's DNA.

165
00:15:37,290 --> 00:15:40,000
- 我是他的儿子 - 不
- I'm... his son. - No.

166
00:15:40,000 --> 00:15:42,040
不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!

167
00:15:42,910 --> 00:15:45,750
- 你是谁  - 发起协议53
What are you? Initiate Protocol 53.

168
00:15:51,870 --> 00:15:54,200
好了 不要动
Now, sorry, just hold still.

169
00:15:54,200 --> 00:15:55,290
你是谁
Who are you?

170
00:15:55,290 --> 00:15:57,790
等等 我不会回答你的问题
Wait. Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait. I won't answer your questions

171
00:15:57,790 --> 00:16:00,450
除非你让我给你注射这个
unless you let me inject you with this.

172
00:16:01,870 --> 00:16:04,660
好了 不要动
All right, don't move.

173
00:16:04,660 --> 00:16:06,450
必须要保守这个秘密
The secret must be guarded.

174
00:16:06,450 --> 00:16:08,700
不要进去 不要进去那里
Don't-don't go in there. Don't you go in there!

175
00:16:08,700 --> 00:16:11,660
不要读那里的东西 不要开灯
Don't read anything in there! Or turn on the lights.

176
00:16:11,660 --> 00:16:15,290
不要访问信息树 也不要查看终端
Don't you access the info tree or look at the terminal.

177
00:16:16,080 --> 00:16:18,580
等等 待在那里
Wait! Just... stay right there.

178
00:16:18,580 --> 00:16:21,790
快停下 我要来抓你了
Stop. I'm coming!

179
00:16:21,790 --> 00:16:23,500
这是什么地方
What is this place?

180
00:16:25,500 --> 00:16:27,620
知道芭波什么时候回来吗
Any idea when Barb will be back?

181
00:16:27,620 --> 00:16:29,200
抱歉 她正在开会
I'm sorry. She's in a meeting.

182
00:16:29,200 --> 00:16:31,620
似乎和垂直整合有关 或者...
Something about vertical integration or--

183
00:16:31,620 --> 00:16:32,910
不是我这个层级能知道的事
Above my pay grade.

184
00:16:32,910 --> 00:16:34,000
我也是
Mine, too.

185
00:16:36,620 --> 00:16:38,450
顺便一说 霍华德先生
By the way, Mr. Howard,

186
00:16:38,450 --> 00:16:41,700
有个和芭波一起工作的新人 亨利
there's a new guy who works with Barb. Henry.

187
00:16:42,500 --> 00:16:44,450
他是你的忠实粉丝
He's a really big fan of yours.

188
00:16:44,450 --> 00:16:46,120
对 亨利
Yes. Henry.

189
00:16:46,790 --> 00:16:49,200
他给我们家打过几次电话
He has called the house a few times.

190
00:16:49,200 --> 00:16:52,540
你介意见见他吗 一会儿就好
Do you mind if I bring him by? Just to meet you for a moment?

191
00:16:52,540 --> 00:16:55,250
当然不介意 能见到粉丝我很高兴
Of course. Yeah. Always happy to meet a fan.

192
00:17:09,370 --> 00:17:11,910
我们的所有成就
All of our work,

193
00:17:11,910 --> 00:17:15,000
都是这次硕果累累的合作促成的
everything that we've accomplished is the result of this fruit-bearing collaboration

194
00:17:15,000 --> 00:17:18,750
我们这些企业志同道合 让美国变得伟大
between like-minded corporations that make America great.

195
00:17:21,080 --> 00:17:25,540
我代表避难所科技公司的 全体员工欢迎大家
On behalf of everyone here at Vault-Tec... welcome.

196
00:17:25,540 --> 00:17:26,620
避难所科技公司

197
00:17:26,620 --> 00:17:28,040
罗科公司

198
00:17:28,040 --> 00:17:29,410
威斯科技公司

199
00:17:29,410 --> 00:17:31,830
大空山

200
00:17:31,830 --> 00:17:34,620
开门见山吧 巴德
Let's call this what it is, Bud.

201
00:17:34,620 --> 00:17:37,200
你的销量没达到要求 你需要资金
Your sales aren't up to snuff,

202
00:17:37,200 --> 00:17:38,290
瑞普康
and you need money.

203
00:17:38,290 --> 00:17:42,330
你也好意思说这话 费雷迪老兄 你开赌场都可能赔钱
You're one to talk, Freddy boy. You could lose money running a casino.

204
00:17:45,410 --> 00:17:46,950
我们的销量挺好的
Our sales are fine.

205
00:17:47,620 --> 00:17:50,580
当然了 和平谈判的谣言 对我们产生了些许负面影响
Sure, rumors of the peace negotiations have set us back a bit,

206
00:17:50,580 --> 00:17:53,160
但我们想为大家提供一个好机会
but we're here to offer you an opportunity.

207
00:17:53,160 --> 00:17:55,580
我们希望大家能合作建设某些避难所
We'd like to collaborate on some of our vaults.

208
00:17:55,580 --> 00:17:57,540
避难所让我很费解
I-I don't get the vaults.

209
00:17:57,540 --> 00:17:59,120
核弹爆发的时候
When it's time to come out,

210
00:17:59,830 --> 00:18:02,910
如果地表上仍然有活人怎么办
what if people are still alive on the surface?

211
00:18:02,910 --> 00:18:04,500
他们会像石器时代的生物一样
They'll be Stone Age creatures.

212
00:18:04,500 --> 00:18:07,250
吃掉从避难所里出来的人
Probably eat whoever steps out of your vaults.

213
00:18:07,250 --> 00:18:09,080
不需要担心那个问题
That isn't an issue.

214
00:18:09,080 --> 00:18:11,790
我们的避难所里 储备了足以生存几个世纪的资源
Our vaults have the resources to survive for centuries.

215
00:18:11,790 --> 00:18:14,580
与此同时 我们的竞争对手
Meanwhile, our competitors-- you know,

216
00:18:15,290 --> 00:18:18,410
也就是没进入避难所的人类 将会死在地表
every other human who isn't us-- will be dead on the surface.

217
00:18:20,620 --> 00:18:24,660
毕竟 说到底 终极的大规模杀伤武器是什么
Because after all, what is the ultimate weapon of mass destruction?

218
00:18:29,250 --> 00:18:31,080
- 时间 - 时间
Time. Time.

219
00:18:32,910 --> 00:18:35,120
时间是顶级掠食者
Time is the apex predator.

220
00:18:35,700 --> 00:18:37,910
万一发生核事故
And in the event of an incident,

221
00:18:37,910 --> 00:18:42,500
时间将成为摧毁所有敌人的武器
time is the weapon with which we will defeat all of our enemies.

222
00:18:43,160 --> 00:18:46,120
我们会以这种方式 赢得资本主义游戏
That is how we will win the great game of capitalism.

223
00:18:46,120 --> 00:18:47,790
不是通过比别人力量更强
Not by outfighting anyone,

224
00:18:48,750 --> 00:18:50,700
而是通过比别人活得更久
but by outliving them.

225
00:18:50,700 --> 00:18:53,700
哪怕你能比地表上的威胁活得久
Even if you outlive all external threats,

226
00:18:53,700 --> 00:18:56,040
但你们的避难所还是有问题
here's my problem with the vaults.

227
00:18:56,040 --> 00:18:58,750
你把一群老鼠关在一个洞穴里
You confine a bunch of rats

228
00:18:58,750 --> 00:19:01,160
关久了 它们就会开始同类相食
in a nest for a long time, they end up eating each other.

229
00:19:01,160 --> 00:19:03,750
所以要怎么保证你的老鼠肯定会比
So who's to say your rats are gonna survive

230
00:19:03,750 --> 00:19:06,040
地表上的那些动物活得更好
better than those animals on the surface?

231
00:19:06,040 --> 00:19:09,120
而且你还没解决根本问题
And you still haven't addressed the fundamental question--

232
00:19:09,120 --> 00:19:11,830
如果这些人可以活一万年...
That is a little shortsighted, I would say.

233
00:19:11,830 --> 00:19:14,500
不 很显然你没有仔细看过数字
I don't need rats for people on the surface.

234
00:19:30,950 --> 00:19:34,330
我希望讨论能带回正轨
If I could perhaps refocus the conversation.

235
00:19:39,000 --> 00:19:41,200
拜托 芭波 纠正他们的错误
Come on, Barb. Set 'em straight.

236
00:19:42,870 --> 00:19:44,870
当我思考未来的时候
When I think about the future,

237
00:19:46,120 --> 00:19:51,040
我会想到我的女儿 珍妮
I think about my daughter... Janey.

238
00:19:53,450 --> 00:19:57,080
我要怎么为她提供一个更好的未来
How do I provide her with a better future?

239
00:19:57,080 --> 00:19:59,870
我们邀请你们来这里 就是为了讨论这个
That's what we've invited you here to discuss.

240
00:20:01,160 --> 00:20:02,250
没错
Yes.

241
00:20:03,250 --> 00:20:06,540
我们要怎么设计避难所里的社会
And how do we design our vault societies

242
00:20:06,540 --> 00:20:10,370
我们的孩子们才会有更好的未来
so our children have that better future?

243
00:20:10,370 --> 00:20:12,750
我建议咱们做好两手准备
I suggest we hedge our bets.

244
00:20:13,160 --> 00:20:15,620
等等 我是这里的监管人
Wait! I am the Overseer here!

245
00:20:15,620 --> 00:20:17,950
你必须听从我的命令
My orders must be followed!

246
00:20:18,660 --> 00:20:21,830
为什么没有用  这是最基本的冲突解决方式
Why isn't this working? This is conflict resolution 101.

247
00:20:21,830 --> 00:20:25,160
- 避难所的其它部分在哪里  - 这就是避难所的其它部分
Where's the rest of the vault? This is the rest of the vault.

248
00:20:26,080 --> 00:20:28,660
我爸爸就是从这里来的吗
Is this where my dad's from?

249
00:20:28,660 --> 00:20:30,370
你永远都不会知道的
You'll never find out.

250
00:20:32,330 --> 00:20:33,950
他要知道了
He's gonna find out.

251
00:20:52,370 --> 00:20:55,450
这些都是巴德的伙伴们 我的伙伴们
These are Bud's Buds.

252
00:20:55,450 --> 00:20:59,410
美国将确保国家存在的使命 外包给了私营部门
My Buds. America outsourced the survival of this country to the private sector.

253
00:20:59,410 --> 00:21:01,950
但让一个失败的国家继续存在 是很荒谬的
But it would have been insane to keep a failed nation alive.

254
00:21:01,950 --> 00:21:04,080
因此我们只让避难所继续存在...
So, we kept Vault-Tec alive instead.

255
00:21:04,080 --> 00:21:05,790
贝蒂皮尔森 高级助理

256
00:21:05,790 --> 00:21:07,910
也就是一群受监督的初级主管
A well-trained staff of highly supervised junior executives

257
00:21:07,910 --> 00:21:09,500
汉克麦克莱恩 高级助理

258
00:21:09,500 --> 00:21:11,160
他们都出身于我的培训项目
from my own assistant training program.

259
00:21:11,160 --> 00:21:14,000
全人类的未来都依赖于一样东西
Because the future of humanity comes down to one word:

260
00:21:15,620 --> 00:21:17,250
管理
Management.

261
00:21:18,950 --> 00:21:23,540
巴德打算建立三个相互连接的避难所
Bud here has an idea for three interconnected vaults.

262
00:21:23,540 --> 00:21:27,290
但我们需要更多的想法 我们需要你们的想法
But we need more ideas. We need your ideas.

263
00:21:27,290 --> 00:21:32,160
正是竞争精神让我们的公司如此伟大
Because it was the spirit of competition that made our companies great,

264
00:21:32,160 --> 00:21:37,580
因此我提议将这种竞争精神 引入到这个解决方案之中
and I propose we bring that same spirit of competition to our solution.

265
00:21:41,500 --> 00:21:45,700
整个美国有一百多个避难所
We have over a hundred vaults spread across America.

266
00:21:47,370 --> 00:21:50,620
你们可以各自统治几个避难所
Enough for each of you to claim several,

267
00:21:50,620 --> 00:21:54,660
在那里你们可以按照自己的想法
where you can play out your own ideas

268
00:21:54,660 --> 00:21:57,370
创建最适合人类生存的完美社会
for how to create the perfect conditions for humanity.

269
00:21:57,370 --> 00:22:00,370
无论你们想怎么做 外人都不会知道
Whatever you want to do, no one needs to know.

270
00:22:03,200 --> 00:22:05,200
希望有人能想出最佳方案
And may the best idea win.

271
00:22:09,830 --> 00:22:14,250
那32号和33号避难所是什么 只是一群被操控的人吗
So what's Vault 32 and 33? Just people to be controlled?

272
00:22:14,250 --> 00:22:18,120
什么 才不是呢 你说得好像这事很不道德一样
What? No! When you put it like that, it sounds downright morally questionable.

273
00:22:18,120 --> 00:22:22,700
他们是我们的繁殖池 是人力资源和研发的终极形式
They're our breeding pool, the ultimate expression of HR R&D.

274
00:22:22,700 --> 00:22:27,660
经过基因挑选 他们会与我的伙伴们 繁育后代 培养一群超级管理者
Genetically selected to breed with my Buds to create a class of super managers.

275
00:22:27,660 --> 00:22:30,580
一群积极乐观 能苦中作乐的人
People with positivity, people who make lemonade.

276
00:22:30,580 --> 00:22:34,290
我们把地表清除干净后 这群人将会统治地球
People who will inherit the Earth after we've wiped the surface clean.

277
00:22:38,200 --> 00:22:39,830
地表被清除干净了
We wiped the surface clean?

278
00:22:40,700 --> 00:22:44,540
我们可以故意让某个避难所人口过多
We could intentionally overcrowd a vault so people have

279
00:22:44,540 --> 00:22:48,500
让他们为了生存而互相竞争
to compete to survive inside it.

280
00:22:49,120 --> 00:22:53,160
不 我们在研发一种机器人 它能将牛奶送到门口
We have been developing a robot that delivers milk to the front door.

281
00:22:53,160 --> 00:22:56,580
这种机器人很聪明 我希望它能管理某个避难所
It's quite intelligent. I would like to see a vault governed by it.

282
00:22:56,580 --> 00:23:00,410
不如将非法移民塞进某个避难所 把他们变成
What about using a vault to develop a super-mutant soldier

283
00:23:00,410 --> 00:23:01,870
基因突变的超级战士
using illegal immigrants?

284
00:23:01,870 --> 00:23:04,700
我们可以将治疗精神病的药物 放入空气供应设备
We could pump psychotropic drugs into the air supply.

285
00:23:04,700 --> 00:23:06,910
我们可以将父母和孩子分开
We could separate parents and children,

286
00:23:06,910 --> 00:23:09,160
只有最聪明的孩子能活到成年
and only the smartest kids reach adulthood.

287
00:23:10,080 --> 00:23:11,080
这想法挺有趣的
It's a fun idea.

288
00:23:11,620 --> 00:23:14,700
世界末日有着很大的赚头
There's a lot of earning potential with the end of the world.

289
00:23:15,540 --> 00:23:19,160
但要我们进行如此重大的投资
But we're talking about making a significant investment

290
00:23:19,160 --> 00:23:21,000
不能只基于假设
based on a hypothetical.

291
00:23:21,000 --> 00:23:23,370
你要如何保证结果呢
How can you guarantee results?

292
00:23:24,370 --> 00:23:26,540
我们会亲自投下核弹
By dropping the bomb ourselves.

293
00:23:32,040 --> 00:23:33,330
霍华德先生
Mr. Howard?

294
00:23:33,330 --> 00:23:35,580
我喜欢这个...

295
00:23:35,580 --> 00:23:36,870
霍华德先生
Mr. Howard?

296
00:23:39,330 --> 00:23:41,160
你还好吗 霍华德先生
Everything all right, Mr. Howard?

297
00:23:41,830 --> 00:23:42,910
没事
Uh, fine.

298
00:23:42,910 --> 00:23:45,540
我没事 贝蒂
I'm-I'm... I'm-I'm fine, Betty.

299
00:23:46,790 --> 00:23:48,870
他很兴奋能见到你
He is so excited to meet you.

300
00:23:52,540 --> 00:23:54,950
核事故将会是一场悲剧
A nuclear event would be a tragedy...

301
00:23:55,790 --> 00:23:57,790
但也是一个机会
but also, an opportunity.

302
00:23:58,580 --> 00:24:01,700
或许是史上最大的机会
Perhaps the greatest opportunity in history.

303
00:24:01,700 --> 00:24:06,200
当我们成为唯一的幸存者时 就没有人能与我们争斗了
Because when we are the only ones left, there will be no one to fight.

304
00:24:08,540 --> 00:24:10,660
我们将成为真正的垄断者
A true monopoly.

305
00:24:11,450 --> 00:24:14,450
霍华德先生 我是你的忠实粉丝
Mr. Howard. Huge fan. I'm Henry, but, uh,

306
00:24:14,450 --> 00:24:16,950
我是亨利 但是大家叫我汉克
everyone calls me Hank.

307
00:24:25,120 --> 00:24:28,750
你爸爸已经活了很久了
Your father has been around for a very long time.

308
00:24:34,120 --> 00:24:36,870
他隶属的组织自以为掌握了
Part of an organization that thought they had the answers

309
00:24:36,870 --> 00:24:39,000
解决世上所有难题的最好办法
to all the world's problems.

310
00:24:43,040 --> 00:24:46,540
还记得你开枪 打乔伊托罗脸那场戏吗
You know, that scene? That scene where you shoot Joey Toro in the face?

311
00:24:48,620 --> 00:24:51,700
“Feo  fuerte y formal”
Feo, fuerte y formal.

312
00:24:52,250 --> 00:24:57,410
我们可以借此机会让战争消失
This is our chance to make war obsolete.

313
00:24:57,410 --> 00:25:00,910
我们当前的社会结构
Because in our current societal configuration,

314
00:25:00,910 --> 00:25:03,830
是在无意间自由形成的
which took shape without intentional guidance,

315
00:25:03,830 --> 00:25:05,660
人类之间充满摩擦
we have friction.

316
00:25:06,830 --> 00:25:09,700
充满冲突 总是战争不断
We have conflict, and we have war.

317
00:25:12,080 --> 00:25:14,080
而战争...
And war, well...

318
00:25:20,080 --> 00:25:22,080
战争永远不会改变
War never changes.

319
00:25:26,080 --> 00:25:27,830
那段太棒了...
I was just wondering, if-if...

320
00:25:27,830 --> 00:25:30,500
我在想 如果你不介意
if you don't mind,

321
00:25:30,500 --> 00:25:34,000
我不想这样打扰你 但你能给我签个名吗
um, I hate to be that guy, but, do you think you could give me an autograph?

322
00:25:37,160 --> 00:25:40,290
他从没告诉过你他来自哪里
He never told you where he's really from,

323
00:25:40,290 --> 00:25:41,910
来自什么时代
when he's from.

324
00:25:43,370 --> 00:25:45,700
他也没告诉过你妈妈
He never told your mother, either.

325
00:25:55,910 --> 00:25:58,120
你对我妈妈了解多少
What do you know about my mother?

326
00:25:59,450 --> 00:26:01,040
她和你很像
She was like you.

327
00:26:02,040 --> 00:26:06,370
她很善良 慈爱 充满好奇心
She was kind, loving. Curious.

328
00:26:06,370 --> 00:26:09,040
你会来地表不也是因为好奇吗
Isn't that why you came to the surface really?

329
00:26:09,790 --> 00:26:12,660
当然也是为了救你父亲
Partly to rescue your father, but...

330
00:26:12,660 --> 00:26:14,540
可你知道我为什么要把他抓来吗
to know why I took him?

331
00:26:35,870 --> 00:26:37,080
谢谢
Thank you.

332
00:26:45,250 --> 00:26:47,040
等等 戴恩 他们要派你去吗
Wait. Dane, they're sending you?

333
00:26:47,950 --> 00:26:50,040
这是对我的惩罚
Punishment for what I did to myself.

334
00:26:51,200 --> 00:26:52,160
嘿
Hey.

335
00:26:54,700 --> 00:26:59,000
我当时很怕进入外界 完全没想到他们会归罪于你
I was just scared of going into the Wilds. I had no idea they'd blame you for it. I...

336
00:27:00,330 --> 00:27:01,750
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.

337
00:27:05,450 --> 00:27:06,540
不用
Don't be.

338
00:27:07,290 --> 00:27:09,120
我本想继续执行那个任务
I was meant to go on that mission.

339
00:27:11,410 --> 00:27:12,660
我遇到了一个人
I met someone.

340
00:27:13,450 --> 00:27:15,620
但现在她正身陷险境
But right now, she's walking into danger.

341
00:27:17,160 --> 00:27:20,160
所以你才会回来 为了救她
That's why you came back. To rescue her.

342
00:27:21,500 --> 00:27:23,500
我要和她一起离开
I'm leaving with her.

343
00:27:23,500 --> 00:27:25,500
我要去她的故乡
I am going back to where she came from.

344
00:27:26,540 --> 00:27:27,870
一个避难所
A vault.

345
00:27:27,870 --> 00:27:30,370
那里很和平 很安全
It's a place that's peaceful... and safe.

346
00:27:30,370 --> 00:27:32,620
没有人需要参加战争
Where nobody ever goes to war.

347
00:27:34,870 --> 00:27:36,200
怎么了
What?

348
00:27:36,750 --> 00:27:39,080
- 废物 出发  - 遵命 长官
- Maggots, clear out! - Yes, sir!

349
00:27:39,080 --> 00:27:40,410
走吧

350
00:27:44,370 --> 00:27:46,160
没有哪里是安全的 麦克斯
There's nowhere safe, Max.

351
00:27:47,450 --> 00:27:50,540
世上不存在乐土 要是有就好了
And there's no leaving. I wish there was.

352
00:28:33,370 --> 00:28:37,290
罗丝很聪明 就像你一样
Rose was so clever. Like you.

353
00:28:39,410 --> 00:28:42,290
露西 你妈妈发现
Lucy, your mother discovered

354
00:28:42,290 --> 00:28:46,160
某个东西抽走了避难所的水
that something was siphoning the vault's water away.

355
00:28:48,120 --> 00:28:49,830
通过那条线索
From that one clue,

356
00:28:49,830 --> 00:28:55,580
她推断出地表已经重建文明
she deduced that maybe... civilization had returned to the surface.

357
00:29:02,250 --> 00:29:04,700
当她告诉她的丈夫时
When she told her husband,

358
00:29:04,700 --> 00:29:08,330
他说她的想法太荒唐了
he said it was a ridiculous idea,

359
00:29:09,080 --> 00:29:10,700
并让她不要告诉任何人
and that she should tell no one.

360
00:29:10,700 --> 00:29:12,620
露西 咱们走吧 走吧
Lucy, let's go. Let's--

361
00:29:12,620 --> 00:29:17,870
就在那一刻 她意识到了 她身为监管人的丈夫
And that's when she realized that her husband, the Overseer,

362
00:29:17,870 --> 00:29:19,370
在隐瞒某些事情
was hiding things.

363
00:29:19,790 --> 00:29:21,700
露西 咱们走吧 离开这里
Lucy, let's go. Let's get out of here.

364
00:29:21,700 --> 00:29:23,120
所以她逃跑了
So she ran away.

365
00:29:24,120 --> 00:29:25,950
就像你一样 露西
Like you did, Lucy.

366
00:29:28,540 --> 00:29:30,910
并带着孩子们一起离开了
And took her children.

367
00:29:31,500 --> 00:29:34,250
然后她找到了一座美好的城市
And she found this wonderful city

368
00:29:34,250 --> 00:29:36,450
那里有着避难所承诺的一切
that was everything the vaults had promised to be.

369
00:29:36,450 --> 00:29:37,750
她在说谎
She is lying!

370
00:29:39,540 --> 00:29:42,450
但她的丈夫找到了她
But then, her husband came after her.

371
00:29:42,450 --> 00:29:45,330
她不肯跟丈夫回家
And when she decided not to return home,

372
00:29:46,870 --> 00:29:48,500
于是他带走了孩子...
he took the children.

373
00:29:51,370 --> 00:29:54,160
并放火将整个城市烧成了废墟
And he burned that city to the ground.

374
00:30:00,250 --> 00:30:03,290
- 沙荫市 - 她在撒谎 露西
Shady Sands. She's lying, Lucy.

375
00:30:04,370 --> 00:30:06,870
避难所科技公司就是这么对竞争者的
That's how Vault-Tec deals with competition.

376
00:30:07,620 --> 00:30:09,950
他们两百年前就做过这种事
Just like they did 200 years ago.

377
00:30:34,540 --> 00:30:39,040
露西 你带来的是冷核聚变
Lucy? What you brought me is cold fusion.

378
00:30:39,040 --> 00:30:41,410
- 是无限的能量 - 露西
- It's limitless energy. - Lucy?

379
00:30:41,410 --> 00:30:44,040
- 我们可以一起建造世界 - 她是杀人犯
- And we can buil dour own world. - She's a murderer.

380
00:30:44,040 --> 00:30:46,080
- 露西 看着我 - 这个世界可以变得更好
- Lucy, look at me. - It could be a better world.

381
00:30:46,080 --> 00:30:49,450
- 这里将会有干净的水 药物和能源 - 她入侵了我们的家园
- It has clean water and medicine-- and power. - She invaded our home.

382
00:30:49,450 --> 00:30:50,870
- 造福每一个人 - 露西...
- But for everyone. - Lucy?

383
00:30:50,870 --> 00:30:54,080
- 她杀了我们的同胞... - 当年避难所科技公司买下我的发明
- Because when Vault-Tec... our people... - She killed...bought my research...

384
00:30:54,080 --> 00:30:56,160
将其变为他们的所有物
...they made it proprietary,

385
00:30:56,160 --> 00:30:59,040
只有受信任的避难所科技公司的走狗
so only a trusted Vault-Tec minion

386
00:30:59,040 --> 00:31:02,910
- 才能激活冷核聚变 - 不要听她的
- can activate cold fusion. - Do not listen to her.

387
00:31:05,500 --> 00:31:09,040
我只想让他告诉我访问码
All I need is for him to give me the code.

388
00:31:09,040 --> 00:31:11,330
露西 看着我
Lucy, look at me!

389
00:31:12,080 --> 00:31:14,870
看着我 露西
Look at me! Lucy!

390
00:31:27,200 --> 00:31:28,500
我妈妈...
My mother.

391
00:31:32,000 --> 00:31:33,660
她后来怎么了
What happened to her?

392
00:31:37,200 --> 00:31:38,700
我想你知道
I think you know.

393
00:31:58,540 --> 00:31:59,540
露西...
Lucy?

394
00:32:25,870 --> 00:32:27,290
露西...
Lucy?

395
00:32:28,620 --> 00:32:30,250
她在撒谎 露西
She's lying, Lucy.

396
00:32:35,540 --> 00:32:37,370
告诉她访问码
Just give her the code.

397
00:32:53,200 --> 00:32:54,620
告诉她访问码
Give her the code.

398
00:33:06,120 --> 00:33:07,830
告诉她访问码 爸爸
Give her the code, Dad.

399
00:33:41,950 --> 00:33:43,160
访问码 101097

400
00:33:43,160 --> 00:33:44,120
员工身份

401
00:33:57,580 --> 00:33:59,290
避难所科技

402
00:33:59,290 --> 00:34:02,290
启动中...

403
00:34:53,660 --> 00:34:54,660
冷冻中的巴德的伙伴们 再活化状态

404
00:34:54,660 --> 00:34:55,910
贝蒂皮尔森 完成

405
00:34:55,910 --> 00:34:57,160
汉克麦克莱恩 完成

406
00:34:57,160 --> 00:34:58,410
斯蒂芬妮哈珀 完成

407
00:35:04,200 --> 00:35:07,200
很高兴认识你 但我必须回家了
Well, it was great meeting you. I actually have to get back home.

408
00:35:07,200 --> 00:35:09,120
你不能回家 汉克之子
You can't go home, son of Hank.

409
00:35:11,080 --> 00:35:12,160
不
No.

410
00:35:15,370 --> 00:35:16,830
你知道得太多了
Not with what you've learned.

411
00:35:19,620 --> 00:35:22,540
那你要把我关在这里吗
So you're just-- you're just gonna keep me here?

412
00:35:22,540 --> 00:35:24,910
等我们都做好返回地表的准备 就放你出去
Just until we're all ready to go to the surface.

413
00:35:24,910 --> 00:35:26,700
那可能要等几百年呢
That could be hundreds of years.

414
00:35:26,700 --> 00:35:30,120
没错 所以我建议你 在你爸爸的冷冻舱中等待
True. That's why I'd suggest you wait it out in your dad's pod.

415
00:35:30,950 --> 00:35:32,540
除非你想被活活饿死
Unless you want to starve to death.

416
00:35:32,540 --> 00:35:36,120
除了偶尔会出现大虫子之外 这里没什么食物
Not much food in here, except the occasional very large bug.

417
00:35:37,000 --> 00:35:39,250
要我选的话 我肯定会选择让自己休眠
I'd certainly put myself to sleep if I could.

418
00:36:16,160 --> 00:36:18,250
我当时必须那么做
I did what was necessary...

419
00:36:20,330 --> 00:36:22,080
我是为了拯救同胞
...to save our people.

420
00:36:24,000 --> 00:36:25,660
那边那个女人
And that woman over there...

421
00:36:28,160 --> 00:36:30,250
她和我没区别
She's no different than me.

422
00:36:40,950 --> 00:36:43,160
冷核聚变 准备就绪

423
00:36:54,950 --> 00:36:55,950
测试

424
00:36:58,620 --> 00:36:59,870
飞行器靠近中
Incoming aircraft.

425
00:37:03,660 --> 00:37:04,830
兄弟会
The Brotherhood?

426
00:37:05,410 --> 00:37:07,000
堵住门
Barricade the doors!

427
00:37:07,870 --> 00:37:09,580
不能让他们进来
Don't let anyone in here!

428
00:37:10,330 --> 00:37:11,330
走吧
Let's move!

429
00:37:11,330 --> 00:37:13,870
- 快点 听我倒数 快 - 出动
Move out, move out, move out.

430
00:37:17,200 --> 00:37:20,790
露西 我曾经很爱你的母亲
Lucy? I loved your mother.

431
00:37:23,200 --> 00:37:26,120
但她离开家时 她就不配做你的母亲了
But she stopped being your mother when she left home.

432
00:37:28,200 --> 00:37:31,700
她让你置于危险之中
When she took you into danger.

433
00:38:07,540 --> 00:38:08,620
小心炮弹
Incoming!

434
00:38:13,250 --> 00:38:14,790
你见过地上是什么样子了
You've seen what it's like up here.

435
00:38:25,500 --> 00:38:29,250
每个人都活在恐惧中 活得很悲惨
Everyone equally afraid, equally miserable.

436
00:38:37,080 --> 00:38:40,290
为了生存 无所不用其极
Forced to do horrible things in order to survive.

437
00:38:41,580 --> 00:38:42,870
露西...
Lucy...

438
00:38:44,660 --> 00:38:46,500
我当时不得不做出选择
I had to make a choice.

439
00:38:49,750 --> 00:38:53,450
毁掉他们的残暴世界 保护我们的和平世界
Between their violent world and our peaceful one.

440
00:38:54,290 --> 00:38:57,040
新加州共和国总部

441
00:38:57,040 --> 00:39:02,080
露西 我知道我做出了正确的选择
And I believe, Lucy, I know I made the right choice. Go!

442
00:40:16,120 --> 00:40:20,200
如果这个世界千疮百孔 是因为人类不停地争斗
If the problem with the world is factions endlessly fighting,

443
00:40:20,200 --> 00:40:21,500
不停打仗
endlessly at war,

444
00:40:21,500 --> 00:40:25,250
那最好的解决方式 不就是除掉这群人吗
then what is the solution but to get rid of the factions?

445
00:40:26,040 --> 00:40:27,660
由我们亲自接管这个世界
To make the world us,

446
00:40:28,500 --> 00:40:30,120
重塑这个世界
only ours to shape.

447
00:41:41,040 --> 00:41:44,250
你们觉得自己穿着装甲 就战无不胜了 是吗
I'll bet that outfit makes y'all feel like a big man, don't it?

448
00:41:45,540 --> 00:41:50,370
我懂你们的感受 我过去也穿过那种装甲
Well, I know 'cause, well, I used to wear one back in the day.

449
00:41:51,160 --> 00:41:53,580
不过它有一个问题
There was only one problem with it.

450
00:41:54,250 --> 00:41:58,500
它的焊接有一处缺陷
There was a flaw in the welding

451
00:41:58,500 --> 00:42:01,200
就在胸板下方
just below the chest plate.

452
00:42:01,200 --> 00:42:03,700
不知道你们的新型装甲 是否修正了这个缺陷
I wonder if they fixed that in this new model?

453
00:42:13,500 --> 00:42:15,120
看来没有
I guess not.

454
00:42:28,040 --> 00:42:30,250
- 打到他了吗  - 我什么都看不到
Did you get him? I can't see shit.

455
00:42:39,620 --> 00:42:40,950
那个尸鬼在哪里
Find that fucking ghoul.

456
00:42:56,410 --> 00:42:59,870
打开门 露西 打开门 我们回家吧
Open the door, Lucy. Open the door, let's go home.

457
00:43:01,910 --> 00:43:03,200
我们回家吧
Let's go home.

458
00:43:09,700 --> 00:43:11,040
我们回家吧
Let's go home.

459
00:43:25,620 --> 00:43:26,580
露西
Lucy.

460
00:43:33,330 --> 00:43:35,950
拜托 打开门 露西
Please. Open the door, Lucy.

461
00:43:56,620 --> 00:43:59,120
露西
Lucy. Lucy.

462
00:44:00,040 --> 00:44:02,290
露西
Lucy?

463
00:44:02,290 --> 00:44:05,750
嘿 我是她爸爸 你能带我们离开这里吗
Hey. Hey. I'm her father. Can you get us out of here?

464
00:44:08,660 --> 00:44:10,660
露西 走吧 快走
Lucy, let's go. Come on,

465
00:44:10,660 --> 00:44:13,540
- 我们必须离开这里 - 等等 不行 不能和他一起
- we got to get out of here. - Wait. No. Not with him.

466
00:44:13,540 --> 00:44:15,120
为什么 你什么意思
Why not with him? What do you mean?

467
00:44:15,120 --> 00:44:16,540
因为就是他 他...
Because it was him. He...

468
00:44:18,080 --> 00:44:19,580
- 什么  - 就是他
- What? - It was him.

469
00:44:19,580 --> 00:44:21,080
- 他怎么了  - 他...
- What was him? - He...

470
00:44:22,910 --> 00:44:24,330
露西 怎么了
Lucy, what?

471
00:44:27,330 --> 00:44:28,750
沙荫市
Shady Sands.

472
00:44:56,000 --> 00:44:57,370
就是他害的
It was him.

473
00:45:02,910 --> 00:45:04,330
对不起
I'm sorry.

474
00:45:10,830 --> 00:45:14,120
露西 你要跟我走
Lucy. You're coming with me.

475
00:45:17,700 --> 00:45:19,040
不
No!

476
00:45:21,120 --> 00:45:24,700
嘿 麦克斯 醒醒
Hey, Max. Max. Max, wake up.

477
00:45:37,160 --> 00:45:39,580
你现在明白这里 会对人们产生怎样的影响了吧
You see what this place does to people?

478
00:45:41,250 --> 00:45:43,250
我是你爸爸 露西
I'm your father, Lucy.

479
00:45:47,000 --> 00:45:49,040
你千里迢迢来这里救我
You came all this way for me.

480
00:45:55,870 --> 00:45:57,700
你不会伤害我的
You're not gonna hurt me.

481
00:46:12,330 --> 00:46:15,040
还想要签名吗 小亨利
Oh, you want another autograph, Young Henry?

482
00:46:16,450 --> 00:46:20,290
“Feo  fuerte y formal”
Feo, fuerte y formal.

483
00:46:23,120 --> 00:46:26,750
你女儿告诉我她姓麦克莱恩时...
When your daughter said her last name was MacLean, well,

484
00:46:26,750 --> 00:46:30,660
我无法相信就是那个麦克莱恩
I just couldn't believe it was the MacLean.

485
00:46:30,660 --> 00:46:34,040
这家伙以前会帮我老婆取干洗的衣服
Hell, this kid used to pick up my wife's dry cleaning.

486
00:46:35,290 --> 00:46:38,450
两百年来 我一直想要
Now, I've waited over 200 years

487
00:46:38,450 --> 00:46:42,450
问某人一个问题
to ask somebody one question.

488
00:46:43,830 --> 00:46:46,250
我的家人在哪里
Where's my fucking family?

489
00:47:05,870 --> 00:47:06,950
成吧
Yeah.

490
00:47:12,000 --> 00:47:15,700
嘿 麦克斯
Hey. Max.

491
00:47:16,290 --> 00:47:17,540
麦克斯 醒醒
Hey, hey. Hey, Max. Max, wake up.

492
00:47:17,540 --> 00:47:19,450
拜托 醒醒
Come on, wake up.

493
00:47:19,450 --> 00:47:21,790
醒醒 拜托了
Wake up! God.

494
00:47:23,200 --> 00:47:25,500
醒来吧 拜托
Come on. Come on!

495
00:47:26,200 --> 00:47:29,120
拜托 求你了
Come on! Please!

496
00:47:45,080 --> 00:47:46,910
战争永远不会改变
War never changes.

497
00:47:48,120 --> 00:47:50,290
遥望整个废土
You look out at this Wasteland,

498
00:47:51,160 --> 00:47:53,000
一片混乱
looks like chaos.

499
00:47:57,620 --> 00:48:00,290
但无论何时 总有大人物在暗中掌舵
But there's always somebody behind the wheel.

500
00:48:01,950 --> 00:48:03,950
我必须要和那个大人物谈谈
And that's who I want to talk to.

501
00:48:06,750 --> 00:48:08,330
你爸爸正要去找那家伙
That's where your daddy is headed.

502
00:48:08,910 --> 00:48:10,290
但你放走了他
But you let him go.

503
00:48:10,290 --> 00:48:15,200
追踪丧家犬 比直接问他要去哪里更简单
Well, it's easier to track a stuck pig than to ask it where it's off to.

504
00:48:18,750 --> 00:48:20,790
你想知道 我是怎么认识你爸爸的 对不对
You want to know how I know your daddy, don't you?

505
00:48:21,290 --> 00:48:25,450
这么说吧 你们的那个迷你家园
Let's just say that everything about your whole little world

506
00:48:25,450 --> 00:48:27,660
早在两百年前就被设计好了
was decided over 200 years ago.

507
00:48:31,950 --> 00:48:34,540
你可以选择陪他留在这里
Now, you can stay here with him,

508
00:48:34,540 --> 00:48:37,080
等他的装甲朋友占领了这里
but when his tin can soldier friends take this place--

509
00:48:37,080 --> 00:48:39,080
他们会毫不留情
and they gonna take this place--

510
00:48:39,910 --> 00:48:42,830
杀光这里所有人 包括你
they will kill you and everybody here.

511
00:48:53,660 --> 00:48:56,250
你也可以选择去见你的创造者
Or you could come meet your makers.

512
00:49:45,410 --> 00:49:46,830
你要一起来吗
You coming?

513
00:49:57,700 --> 00:49:59,120
嘿 麦克斯
Hey.

514
00:50:01,500 --> 00:50:02,750
起来
Get up.

515
00:50:07,910 --> 00:50:09,080
麦克斯
Max.

516
00:50:12,120 --> 00:50:13,540
我会去找你的
I'll find you.

517
00:50:35,910 --> 00:50:37,410
走吧
Okey-dokey.

518
00:50:47,830 --> 00:50:52,250
冷核聚变 准备就绪

519
00:51:15,120 --> 00:51:16,330
露西
Lucy.

520
00:51:23,370 --> 00:51:24,580
露西
Lucy.

521
00:51:40,450 --> 00:51:41,660
露西
Lucy.

522
00:51:56,830 --> 00:51:57,950
罗丝
Rose.

523
00:52:17,580 --> 00:52:19,120
冷核聚变 已激活

524
00:52:52,700 --> 00:52:54,540
我们成功了 罗丝
We did it, Rose.

525
00:53:34,910 --> 00:53:39,330
你觉得你的兄弟会 会用无限能量做什么
What do you suppose your Brotherhood would do with infinite power?

526
00:53:44,040 --> 00:53:47,040
你或许能阻止他们 或许不能
Maybe you can stop them. Maybe you can't.

527
00:53:51,200 --> 00:53:53,200
或许你能做的只有尝试
Maybe all you can do is try.

528
00:54:22,580 --> 00:54:24,000
那是他们的首领吗
Is that their leader?

529
00:54:25,580 --> 00:54:26,790
是的

530
00:54:28,250 --> 00:54:29,450
你杀了她
You killed her.

531
00:54:30,750 --> 00:54:32,410
不是的 戴恩
No. Dane.

532
00:54:33,120 --> 00:54:36,410
马克西姆斯万岁 他将就此成为骑士
All hail Maximus! That shalt be Knight hereafter!

533
00:54:36,830 --> 00:55:02,750
马克西姆斯骑士万岁
All hail Knight Maximus!

534
00:55:41,290 --> 00:55:44,500
好莱坞 由核子可乐赞助

535
00:59:08,330 --> 00:59:10,330
字幕翻译:涅伽达

536
00:59:10,330 --> 00:59:12,410
创意监督 杨婕

